Jason Mount

Web Developer / Teaching and Learning Specialist

expert written and verbal skills • computer savvy • focused on data driven research and responsive planning • clear and engaging presentation style

BIO

Patient and analytical self starter with twenty years of experience In the field of teaching, learning, and linguistics. Dedicated to service and confident in both live, interactive work as well as extended projects that require attention to detail.

CONTACT



(917) 743-9139



jmount722@gmail.com



St. Petersburg, FL

EDUCATION

The Ohio State University Columbus, OH

B.A. English Literature March 2002

New York University New York, NY

M.A. TESOL May 2010

Massachusetts Institute of **Technology** Remote Campus

Professional Certificate in Coding: November 2023 (expected)

INTERESTS

A polyglot and daily runner. A golfer and two-time Ironman. Lover of literature, the outdoors, and complex projects.

Experience

Editor —Lee Toledo Law, Washington D.C.

November 2022--PRESENT

Edit legal documents for style, form, and rhetoric. Provide language instruction to the legal team.

Adjunct Professor —St. Petersburg College, Clearwater, FL

October 2022--PRESENT

Teach semester sections of Grammar, Advanced Reading, Speaking and Listening and Academic Writing for the Office of Professional Studies

ESL Teacher — The City of New York, New York, NY

SEPTEMBER 2010--AUGUST 2022

- Oversaw bi-ilingual communications between stakeholders in Title I schools with significant immigrant populations.
- Created curricula, assessments, and educational roadmaps for multicultural, multilingual groups of students.
- Coached baseball and soccer in the Public School and Small School Athletic Leagues.

Teacher Development Coach — NYC Teaching Fellows, New York, NY SUMMERS 2017-2019

- Observed, evaluated, and provided feedback to prospective teachers through the New York City Teaching Fellows training program.
- Conducted face to face and written coaching sessions with prospective teachers.

Lead Instructor — NYC Teaching Academies, New York, NY

JANUARY 2020-AUGUST 2021

Facilitated training sessions in classroom management, assessment, curriculum design and discussion techniques to prospective New York City Teachers.

ESL Teacher — The United Nations, New York, NY

JANUARY 2008 - AUGUST 2010

Taught English in the Language and Communications Programme. Courses included "Advanced Listening and Speaking," "English for Correspondence," and various reading and writing courses.

ESL Teacher — Bronx Community College, Bronx, NY

JANUARY 2007 - AUGUST 2010

Taught English as a Second Language in the Adult Basic Education program.

Adjunct Instructor, ESL— Queensborough C.C., Flushing, NY

MAY 2007 - DECEMBER 2007

Instructed college prep writing courses for incoming Freshman ESL students during Summer and Autumn Semesters.

ESL Teacher — Zoni Language International, New York, NY

APRIL 2004 - MAY 2006

Taught in an intensive immersion program for multinational adult students.

ESL Teacher — Topia Language Zone and Sage Language School, Seoul, Korea

AUGUST 2002 - APRIL 2004

Taught English as a Foreign Language to elementary and High School students.